J. ELLIOT MILLER

717-398-1540 \(\phi\) elliot@alum.bucknell.edu \(\phi\) j-elliot@github.io 741 Chapel Road \(\phi\) Gettysburg, Pennsylvania 17325-8706 18 Nelson Hill \(\phi\) Wassaic, New York 12592

HEADLINE

Wildly experienced with a fresh perspective technologist

BIO

Elliot is a recent *cum laude* computer science graduate of Bucknell University. Through his own startup, he has been involved with the launch and operations of several small businesses. Through his alma mater, he has co-authored one paper and is working on a second. Now that he's preparing to synthesize his technology, science, and business foundations, he laments the lack of time to explore the rich world of late '80s video games.

ELEVATOR PITCH

Elliot combines a broad array of skills and experiences from across disciplines, collar colors, and industries to be a leader who can understand and communicate with people from any position or background, and a worker who can fill almost any professional role and occupy any company space.

EDUCATION

Bucknell University

Bachelor of Arts

Department of Computer Science

College of Arts and Sciences

Minor in Philosophy

Statistical Literacy for the 21st Century (A-); Psychology of Attraction and Relationships (A-); Caribbean Literature (A); Software Engineering and Design (A-); Intro Latin (B); Calculus III (C+); Computer Organization and Programming (B+); Life, Computers, and Everything (A); Discrete Structures (B+); Logic (A); Computer Science Design Project (B+); Operating System Design (B+); Algorithms (B+); Philosophy of Peace and Nonviolence (A); Cognitive Science (AU); Human-Computer Interaction (A-); Symbolic Logic (A); Philosophy of Society and Politics (B+); Consciousness, Self and Mind (A); Wireless System Design (AU).

Harrisburg Area Community College

Associate of Arts

Department of Mathematics and Computer Science

Modern Culture and the Arts (A); Intro to Statistics (A); English Composition (A); Trigonometry (A); Principles of Accounting I (A); Pre-Calculus (A); General Psychology (A); Principles of Accounting II (A); Effective Speaking (A); Applied Calculus for Business (A); Principles of Marketing (A); General Biology I (A); Java Programming (A); Calculus I (A); Introduction to Sociology (A); Intro to Computer Systems (A); Computer Science I (A); Object Oriented Programming (B); Calculus II (A); Beginning Self-Defence (A); General Inorganic Chemistry I (A); Computer Science II (A); Discrete Mathematics

NCCER

May 2013 - April 2014

June 2014 - May 2017 Overall GPA: 3.96/4

June 2016 - May 2019 Overall GPA: 3.55/4

HVAC/R and Construction Training

(A); Linear Algebra (A).

Reference #: 11142092

Core Curricula; Basic Safety; Intro to Construction Math; Intro to Hand Tools; Intro to Power Tools; Intro to Construction Drawings; Basic Communication Skills; Basic Employability Skills; Intro to Material Handling; Intro to HVAC; Trade Mathematics; Copper and Plastic Piping Practices; Soldering and Brazing; Ferrous Metal Piping Practices; Basic Electricity; Intro to Cooling; Intro to Heating; Air Distribution Systems; Commercial Airside Systems; Chimneys, Vents, and Flues; Into to Hydronic Systems; Air Quality Equipment; Leak Detection, Evacuation, Recovery, and Charging; Alternating Current; Basic Electronics; Intro to Control Circuit Troubleshooting; Troubleshooting Gas Heating; Troubleshooting Cooling; Heat Pumps; Basic Installation and Maintenance Practices; Sheet Metal duct Systems; Fiberglass and Flexible Duct Systems; Intro to Photovoltaics; Site Assessment; System Design; System Installation and Inspection; Maintenance and Troubleshooting; Your Role in the Green Environment; 10 Hour Construction Site Safety Orientation; HVAC Level One; Solar Photovoltaics System Installer; Solar Photovoltaic; HVAC Level Two.

Ferris State University

August 2013

Geothermal for Home Certification

Ohio University

Course Work

June 2011 - August 2011

Overall GPA: 4/4

College Algebra (A); Writing and Reading: Gender (A).

PA Highlands Community College

January 2009 - December 2009

Certificate of Office Technology

Overall GPA: 4/4

Microsoft Excel (A); Microsoft Word (A); Microsoft ACCESS (A); Microsoft PowerPoint (A); Theory of Computing (A).

Pennsylvania Department of Education

Various

-Needs work. Are those two really the same department? Also, add grades to ged and detail to drafting.-

GED; Drafting stuff

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Bucknell University

June 2018 - Present

Undergraduate Research

- · Employed SciKitLearn in Python environment to construct machine learning classifiers used in analyzing effectiveness of epsilon-Differential Privacy data protections
- · Engineered custom application to extract and present experiment results across seven variables
- · Presented research at Susquehanna Valley Summer Research Symposium
- · Used supercomputers running custom artificial intelligence to attack ϵ -Differentially Private data

Marissa Deihl, SP

September 2018 - May 2019

Software Developer

- · Collaborated on team using agile and scrum methodologies to build Unity environment educational application
- · Primarily responsible for designing and implementing project goals in code
- · Managed feedback in data driven iterative design and testing process

The Bayeux Group

November 2014 - September 2017

Owner/Manager

· I founded this company to provide business services to hopeful entrepreneurs. Under my management, we directly handled the launch of two companies, and we have been involved with the management of

several other projects. I have personally been handled bookkeeping, scheduling, customer and supply chain management, web and traditional marketing, cost control, sales, strategic planning, product development, risk management, and software and data analytics on behalf of our clients. The company was suspended in order for myself to return to school to further develop my critical problem solving skills and technological knowledge.

- · Developed and implemented business reporting system to monitor project progress and delivery status
- · Supervised and trained new employees for multidisciplinary teams

Dan Kerstetter, Millwork

November 2017 - May 2019

Assistant Woodworker

- · Worked with master woodworker to build and restore custom cabinetry and furniture
- · Used and maintained powered machinery in accordance with OSHA best practices
- · Provided business and technology support to back office operations

VSFS

September 2018 - December 2018

 $Software\ Developer$

- · Worked on software development team to produce gamification simulation of VA hospital operations structure
- · Collaborated exclusively through video conference technology in scrum structure
- · Developed custom artificial intelligence solution for product using Unity tools

Appalachian Brewing Company

April 2014 - August 2017

Assistant to the Kitchen Manager, Head Dessert Chef

- · Managed and prepared pre-product materials to line cooks
- · Held position of leadership and teamwork on line during high-output, mission critical periods demonstrating ability to work well under pressure
- · Occupied maintenance and information technology oriented roles to restore production quickly and efficiently
- · Scheduled employee shifts
- · Ordered and received supply shipments from vendors
- · Organized and stocked supplies to improve efficiency
- · Cleaned and maintained kitchen to professional standards
- \cdot Developed and tested new recipes and provided dessert specials

Ethical H2O

December 2015 - August 2017

Senior Technician

- · Managed company finances and bookkeeping using Quickbooks among other tools
- \cdot Personal selling to current and potential customers, including cold calls
- · Provided service to customers
- · Performed scientific testing of samples for indicators of human health threats and domestic discomfort
- · Administered corporate affairs

Wilson Leather

November 2014 - January 2015

Sales Associate

- · Engaged with customers to determine needs and assist in finding product
- · Handled credit, cash and check transactions in courteous and efficient manner
- · Received, stocked, and arranged product according to specification

Electrician's Assistant, Environmental Technician, Dock Hand

- · Trained by master electrician with over 30 years experience
- · Involved in team pull of high amperage, high voltage new electrical service
- · Collaborated on complete rewire of fitness facility including rebuild of 5000+ sq. ft. lighting provision
- · Engaged in troubleshooting and maintaining institutional and industrial systems and equipment
- · Electrical service and control installation
- · Operated front-end loader
- · Assisted in rigging and lifting operations
- · Removed and sorted institutional waste
- · Received security clearance for restricted areas
- · Operated pallet jacks loading and unloading shipments of supplies
- · Stocked and maintained line food service during high output operation times
- · Assisted with testing of new baked goods and experimented with new recipes

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages C/C++, Java, Python, Visual Basic, C#

Software & Tools Unity, LaTeX, Git, Gimp, Microsoft Office Suit, AutoCAD, Quickbooks

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

HOPE Program

Canine Behavioral Rehabilitation

Dog Handler: Worked with professional dog trainer to train, care for, and rehabilitate unadoptable dogs, preparing them to be placed in permanent homes

Spirit of Gettysburg 5k

Charitable Footrace

- · Wheelchair Race Leader: Rode motorcycle to lead wheelchair section of race through course; entered unchecked traffic, preventing collision with racers
- · Children's Race Leader: Rode bicycle to lead children's race through course
- · Traffic Director: Directed vehicular and pedestrian traffic during pre-race period
- · Score Collator: Received, ordered, and confirmed race results in real time to be used for awards and listings.

Adams County Rescue Mission

Homeless Shelter & Recycling Facility

· Sorter: Helped sort and prepare recycling materials.

HACC Environmental Club

Community College Environmental Organization

· Rock Creek Cleanup: Traveled down local waterway removing trash and debris.

Sinai Hospital, ER7

Emergency Room Administrative Offices

· Administrative Assistant's Assistant: Copied, filed, shredded and recorded hospital documents under the direction of staff; ran errands and delivered messages throughout hospital

ASSOCIATIONS & PROJECTS

Bucknell Student Government Class of 2019 Senator; Advocacy Committee Member; Dining Committee Member; Student Advisory Group Member; Greek Relations Committee Member

Class Tribute Bucknell B

Commemoration Speaker Madeleine Albright

'Ray Response Training

'Ray Resilience

HACC Student Government Association Legislative Chair; Senator; Ethics Committee Chair

Phi Beta Lambda President

Phi Theta Kappa Member

GSA Member

C.A.L.V.I.N. & H.O.B.B.E.S. Member; Student Driver

Dragon Member: DM

ACE Fall Fest 2018; 2017 Escape Room Event: Designed Technology Themed Room

ACM

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Bucknell Community College Scholars Program Scholarship

Graduated cum laude from Bucknell University

Dean's List: Spring 2019; Fall 2016; Spring 2016; Fall 2015; Academic Year 2015

Outstanding Freshman Math/Computer Science Student

Outstanding Sophomore Math/Computer Science Student

2016 Bucknell Community College Scholars Program

SGA Senator of the Semester; Fall 2015

First in Who's Who; Phi Beta Lambda 2016(?) Conference

Second in Strategic Analysis and Decision Making; Phi Beta Lambda 2016(?) Conference

Third in Project Management; Phi Beta Lambda 2016(?) Conference

Benchmark of Excellence: Electrical; Heat Pump; Certified Carbon Monoxide Inspector; Combustion Analysis; HVACR Electrical Plumbing; Basic Refrigeration and Charging Procedures; System Diagnostic and Troubleshooting Procedures

LICENSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

EPA Universal Refrigerant

OSHA 10-hour

PUBLICATIONS AND PRESENTATIONS

Susquehanna Valley Summer Research Symposium Poster (Circuit Game)

(DP Experiment)

INTERESTS

Ballroom Dance; Piano; Violin; Guitar; Architecture; Horticulture; Chemistry; Cybernetics; Electronics; Video Games; Legos

ATHLETICS

Running; Obstacle Courses; Climbing; Combat Sports; Rappelling; One Punch Workout; Cycling